bless me Father , for I have sinned .
the first , I wasn 't able to pray on time yesterday .
second ,
I wrongfully accused a kid for stealing from an elderly at the market .
and the third ,
I sent my mother a letter telling her I 'd visit , but I wasn 't able to .
these are my sins and I ask for forgiveness .
is there anything else ?
No , Father .
you are getting ordained next week .
the strongest of the demon 's temptations are on the last days before priesthood ...
that 's why we 're entering seclusion .
to be away from temptations , I know .
that 's right .
but if you bring in an unclean conscience the walls and ceilings can 't do anything to protect you .
it 's hard to succeed , if you cannot accept your sins , Miguel .
I 'll ask you again .
is there anything else you wish to confess ?
are you certain that you want this ?
I am , Father .
and I offer all of myself to God , because I know he will guide me in everything I do .
God has forgiven you from your sins .
go and be good servant of the Lord .
thank you , Sir .
the japanese are coming !
god has forsaken us !
we have to hide !
they will take us to hell !
the japanese are coming !
god has forsaken us !
we have to hide !
they will take us to hell !
Town of Ildefonso , Quezon
..
thank you Lord ! praise Anghela !
she is healed !
thank you Anghela for healing us !
are you well now ?
thank the Lord !
thank you for answering our prayers .
we 're done for this morning .
come back in the afternoon .
follow me , Father .
we 're done for now . Anghela needs to rest .
haven 't you had enough ?
how many times do we have to prove that Anghela is God 's messenger ?
Papa , please don 't get angry .
I just want to ask you something .
how are you , Anghela ?
I 'm doing well .
are you happy with what you 're doing ?
you 're not having a hard time ?
aren 't they hurting you ?
heal my son ! Please !
ma 'am , ma 'am !
have mercy !
you should have brought him to the hospital !
go ahead , Anghela !
My son ...
thank you ... thank you .
..
somewhere in Luzon
are there people who try to break in here ?
this isn 't for those who want to break in .
it 's for those who want to get out .
seclusion is for seven days .
we get up at six in the morning .
breakfast is at seven .
no loud noises .
no talking .
except when we pray together .
lights off at nine .
do you understand why you 're here ?
you shouldn 't see , hear , smell , or speak to anyone .
because that 's how the Devil 's call begins .
and don 't dare think this will be easy .
countless deacons have failed their seclusion .
I understand .
so , why are you really here ?
to be closer to God .
fasting starts tomorrow .
come out when you 're ready . close the door .
.
* SEKLUSYON * Ripped by teSir ®
Parish of Saint Peter the Apostle
oh , you 've returned .
Good .
you 're better suited for this than the war .
what do you think of the child ?
Anghela is still young .
she doesn 't understand what her parents are making her do .
in other words , you 're not convinced .
I can 't help my doubts .
open your mind , Father .
anyone can be called by God to serve Him , even a young girl like Anghela .
don 't let the war weaken your faith in God .
in the name of the Father , and of the Son , and the Holy Spirit , Amen .
bless us , Oh Lord and these your gifts , which we are about to receive , from your bounty .
through Christ our Lord .
Amen .
Introduce yourselves now .
you won 't be able to speak to each other starting tomorrow .
I 'm Marco , by the way , from San Antonio .
I 'm Carlo . from San Antonio .
I 'm Fabian , from the town of Teresa .
Miguel . Town of San Jose .
who 's there ?
what are you doing there ?
they 're dead !
My God ...
What a tragedy ...
Her eyes are still open ...
Pitiful ...
it 's probably about money again .
I don 't know , but the nun is missing .
I 'm just worried about the child . They haven 't found Anghela yet .
Dear Lord , I hope she is safe .
where could that child be ?
in the name of the father , of the Son , and of the Holy Spirit , Amen .
the angel of the Lord declared unto Mary , and she conceived of the Holy Spirit .
Hail Mary full of grace the Lord is with you .
blessed art thou amongst all women , and blessed is the fruit of your womb , Jesus .
Holy Mary , mother of God , pray for us sinners . Now and at the hour of our death . Amen .
and the word was made flesh .
and dwelt among us Hail Mary full of grace , the Lord is with you .
blessed art thou amongst all women , and blessed is the fruit of your womb , Jesus .
whatever happens tonight , remember that it is the work of the Devil .
He will tempt you and test your faith . Be strong .
don 't mess with me , Demons !
you made me suffer .
you 're worthless .
I 'm not crazy .
Mother ?
you 're worthless ! you 're useless !
Mother , don 't .
you disgust me !
you made me suffer !
Stop ! mother , no !
you 're worthless !
I 'm not crazy !
..
Anghela 's parents were killed .
do you know where Sister Cecila is ?
she 's here now .
What ?
she came as soon as she found out Anghela was here .
but how do we know we could trust the nun ?
don 't worry .
Anghela may be in danger .
Bishop , where is Anghela going ?
sister Cecilia is taking her to a place where no one can harm her .
but Sister Cecilia -
Anghela has known Sister Cecilia for a long time .
there 's no one else more trustworthy than her .
yes , but you didn 't see what I saw -
Calm down , Ricardo ! Calm down .
Father , what is the purpose of your investigation ?
we don 't know Sister Cecilia -
what is the purpose of your investigation ?
to find proof on the miracles of Anghela Santa Ana .
So that the Church could be sure she deserves to be canonized as a living saint .
well then , focus on your investigation .
who told you you could leave me ?
Damn you ! stupid ! Son of a bitch !
don 't you want me anymore ?
this can 't be right . you shouldn 't be here .
you can read the Bishop 's letter again , if you want .
didn 't he know we have deacons doing their seclusion here ?
let 's go , let 's go !
follow me .
all the rooms are taken . this will have to do .
what ?
she 's hungry .
there 's bread in the kitchen .
go down . to the left. second door ...
just follow me .
I 'm not hungry .
don 't stare at me like that .
why are you so cranky , grandpa ?
I 'm not cranky and I 'm not your grandfather .
aren 't you old ?
I used to be a priest . I 'm not a grandpa .
used to be ? you 're not a priest anymore ?
do I still look like a priest ?
no . you look like an old man .
what happened wasn 't your fault .
what did you say ?
are you like this because the Bishop punished you , despite your sacrifices ?
that 's enough .
I understand you , Sandoval .
how did you know my name ?
the Lord is merciful , Sandoval .
he knows you don 't belong here .
your life still has purpose . Just have faith .
Stop !
I 'm lost . do you know where my room is ?
this is it . I remember now .
sleep well .
be careful with fire next time so you don 't burn yourself .
..
I 'm coming with you .
don 't leave me here , please .
I can 't take it anymore .
Carlo my job here is done .
Finish what you 've started .
don 't worry . Anghela is here .
she will help you .
Anghela , I thought about what you said last night .
I understand everyting now .
I wish you well .
be good followers of the Lord .
put your faith in Him .
and you 'll never be hungry or thirsty .
he is all you need .
Father , I was one of the first people Anghela healed .
you mean , you witnessed their sudden rise to riches ?
back then , they didn 't ask for anything in return .
they started charging fees only when the nun came .
Father , to be honest ...
I told the mother about the nun , but she didn 't want to listen .
I saw how she 'd force the child to heal people , even when she 's tired .
they say she got thrown out of the convent because she hurts children and even killed one .
would you know what town Sister Cecilia is from ?
we just want to ask for some bread and ...
Thank you , Lord , for these blessings you 've given us today .
may our gathering be peaceful today and the coming days .
Amen .
this is a miracle. who is she ?
she is the Lord 's messenger .
she 's here under the orders of the Bishop , to save you .
it would be nice if we eat together .
you shouldn 't refuse blessings , brother .
this blessing is enough for me .
Convent of the Immaculate Mother , Camariness
heat some water up and bring it here . Hurry .
yes , Mother .
can 't you wait ?
what is this about ?
I just want to ask about this nun who used to stay here .
get to the point .
I have no time for guessing games .
it 's about Sister Cecilia .
I can 't help you with anything .
I don 't mean to be rude , but I 'm not leaving here until I get some answers .
why are you interested in Sister Cecilia ?
because of Anghela Santa Ana .
I don 't believe she is safe under the nun 's care .
this contains everything you need .
don 't ever come back .
no one is going to believe you , Father .
be careful .
you don 't have to hold your hunger back .
I can manage .
the Lord doesn 't want you to suffer . you don 't have to starve yourself .
she was a teacher at Convent of the ... .
raped by several man
the convent burned down .
her face was burned
I can 't take it anymore . may God help me .
you 're selfish ! you 're bad !
Nilo !
Nanding !
forgive me .
what do you want ?
you 're selfish ! you 're bad !
eat this !
you can have all of it !
remember , O most gracious Virgin Mary , that never was it known that anyone who fled to your protection ,
implored your help or sought your intercession , was left unaided .
Inspired with this confidence , I fly to you ,
O Virgin of virgins , my Mother , to you do I come , before you I stand , sinful and sorrowful .
O Mother of the Word Incarnate , despite not my petitions , but in your mercy hear and answer me . Amen .
you 're not real , Erina !
Miguel , you said you wouldn 't leave me .
you 're not real ! I don 't believe in you !
you 're the Devil ! get away from me !
I will make your like misesable . you son of a bitch !
you will take responsibility ... ..
just tell me if you need anything .
I 'm here to help .
the Lord understands you . you don 't have to forget Erina .
Anghela !
do you want it to stop ?
confess your sins .
what sins ?
Anghela , wait !
my brothers .
they died during the war because of me .
we didn 't have much .
I fought in the war .
I didn 't share the food because I was scared .
I was scared we would run out of food .
heal me , Anghela , and I will do anything you wish .
I promise .
good morning .
good morning , Father .
I just want to talk to you .
what about , Father ?
about your healing .
what do you mean ?
how are you ?
I 'm doing well . things are back to normal .
In fact , better than ever .
I felt a lot better after seeing Anghela .
after that , I had an uncontrollable urge to go to them , to send offerings .
what are you doing here ?
I go here often .
at first , I didn 't know why my feet were taking me here .
then I found out I wasn 't alone .
All of us are Anghela 's devotees .
All of us wholeheartedly praise her .
..
this candle is for my mother . for whom is yours ?
what you feel is normal . the Lord says you shouldn 't suppress it .
please forgive me .
how are you and Fabian ?
why do you ask ?
I think he likes you .
he doesn 't .
or maybe you like him ?
you 're just like your mother . she 's a whore , you 're a whore .
I 'm not a whore .
didn 't you like it when the soldiers raped you ?
shut up !
I 'm so sorry . I didn 't mean it .
get my clothes .
do as I asked .
what are you up to ? why do you have to bother us ?
stop pretending .
you don 't really want to be a priest .
aren 't you here so you don 't have to take care of your mother ?
you bitch .
does it feel good to hit me ?
you 're worthless !
you 're useless ! you disgust me !
you bitch ! you fucking whore !
what ? bitch !
this is what you want , isn 't it ?
Slut !
you don 't need to regret what you did .
there 's nothing wrong if you like playing with little girls .
do you want to play with me ?
I have a bad feeling about ... ..
one of us should leave and report what 's happening .
it 's God 's fault why this happened ... .
Fabian !
I waited so long for you !
why are you leaving me too ?
Miguel !
false prophets ... .. sheep 's clothing ... . ... . ravenous wolves .
Adopted ... . Thrown out of the orphanage ... .
... our faith in the Lord -
Anghela !
tell us who you really are !
calm down .
like I 've said before , Anghela was brought here by the Lord to save you .
is that true ? you 're a Messiah ? The great savior ?
Miguel .
It is you who says so , not me .
Leave ! you 're disturbing us from our seclusion !
we don 't need a Messiah to get closer to God !
you have no right to say that , Miguel .
did you even think about us ?
we 're not as strong as you are .
Anghela has helped us tremendously .
what kind of help ?
don 't you see it ?
why can 't you believe in her ?
if it weren 't for her , I wouldn 't be able to make it here .
if they don 't leave , then I will !
and I 'll make sure the Bishop hears about what 's happening here .
you 've already sacrificed a lot .
you 're so close to becoming a priest .
are you going to risk everything ?
didn 't you leave the woman you love , just for this ? for your ambition ?
you don 't know anything .
didn 't you leave Erina , even when you knew she loved you more than she loved herself ?
I didn 't mean to leave Erina .
I did that because I knew that would be best for her .
is that what you always do ?
make decisions for others ?
you only think of yourself .
nobody wants you to leave .
I just want to be with you .
Anghela 's right .
stay with us . you don 't have to do this .
I have to .
this is a difficult test . I hope I can get through it .
I can 't take it anymore . May God help me .
It 's God 's fault why this happened to me !
this is your doing !
leave your God for me !
Please !
don 't leave me !
Miguel !
this is what you did to me and your child !
suffer with us in hell !
I didn 't know .
as far as I can remember , I knew my mother didn 't want me .
that 's why she killed herself .
what about you ? don 't you want me too ?
I 'll fix everything .
I 'll save you , my daughter .
I was saved a long time ago , Papa .
join me .
after Anghela went missing , people still came here hoping to be healed .
the others stole the jars , thinking that Anghela 's liquid will heal them .
Rejoice ! The Devil is here .
I told you not to come back here .
why doesn 't anyone know about Anghela ?
because no one believes !
if we know , we should do something !
I did try before , look what happened to me !
It is now in God 's hands !
we can 't just leave everything up to God !
Bishop !
Anghela is a false prophet !
go to her ! she is waiting for you .
you don 't have to do that , Father .
the world is at peace . don 't disturb it anymore .
in the name of the Father , the Son and the Holy Spirit . Amen .
Saint Michael the Archangel , defend us in -
are you really happy with what you 're doing , Father ?
do you really want peace ?
don 't you like the war better , so you have a purpose ?
admit it , Ricardo . you loathe your life knowing it 's empty .
shut up !
you 'll get everything you want if you join me .
don 't twist my words , demon .
I 'll die before I choose you over God .
you should 've sworn to me , Father .
as long as people have a choice , they will always choose good .
they will choose what is easy over what is good .
what is good to them is getting what they want , without working for it .
I pity you , Father . you worship a God who is lazy and arrogant .
he left you on your own thinking you 'd always choose what is right .
look at me .
I am the result of people 's free will .
let us bow before the avenging wrath , let us weep before the Judge ,
let us cry out with words of supplication , let us all speak in submission .
Carlo ...
Marco !
Fabien !
we need to leave while there 's still time !
where are they ?
- swear to her , Miguel ! - she is not God whom we should swear to .
God brought Anghela here and He wants us to worship her !
Anghela , that 's enough !
I 'm here , my child .
I 'm never going to leave you , I promise .
do you think I 'm doing this because of you ?
swear to my Lord . he is the one who saved me .
if you 're not going to serve Him , you 're useless to me .
get out of here ! what are you waiting for ?
Leave us !
that 's enough .
give it up .
listen to us .
stop it ! let Anghela go !
open this !
give her back to me , Miguel !
don 't hurt her !
enough !
O Glorious Prince of the heavenly host - -
when did your God answer you ?
- Saint Micheal the Archangel , defend us ... - when did your God answer you ?
in the battle and fearful warfare - -
your God has abandoned you , because I am the fruit of your sins !
what do you want me to do ?
turn against my God ?
No. we 're tired of fighting your God .
I still want you to become a priest and be good followers of your God .
So I 'd have more of my Lord 's people inside the Church .
one day , no one will be able to tell apart who is good and who is evil .
there 's no turning back , Miguel .
are you really giving up your priesthood ?
if that 's what it takes to right the wrong , I 'll do it .
it 's too late .
there 's nothing more you can do , Miguel .
Lord , forgive me .
.
Ripped by teSir